Boma: Hello?
Boma: Sorry, good afternoon, good evening. And am I audible? I don't know what's wrong with my mic.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I hear you.
Boma: Oh, okay.
Boma: Thank God.
Boma: Should we… Begin, or do we wait for Felix?
Chase Wright: I don't know if Felix is coming, so…
Chase Wright: I have merge rights to the repo now.
Chase Wright: But…
Boma: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, I saw that. Okay, let me share my screen then.
Boma: Is it visible?
Chase Wright: Yeah.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: I think most of the PRs, we kind of, like, have, Old spending ones.
Boma: So I'm not sure which particular order we would like to go.
Chase Wright: It doesn't really matter.
Boma: Okay, so we can… But,
Boma: Well, Lido?
Boma: Okay, so we have this, this is… it's for 7pool.
Boma: It's still on… that's… Okay, this is a zecution witness, actually.
Chase Wright: Sorry, what?
Boma: I mean, this is, the debug execution witness, the part of the issue I raised, Think…
Boma: Yeah, this… do we still have anything on it, or we should wait for,
Boma: the stateless, the zkBM team, too.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I mean, I… I only drafted the… the, like, YAML standard portion, right? And the only one who's responded was Tulio, and he requested the keys field be made optional, so I did that.
Chase Wright: But beyond that, like…
Chase Wright: I'm not really the one driving the implementation of this API, so I don't really have… useful input.
Chase Wright: Into how we progress?
Chase Wright: So…
Boma: Okay.
Chase Wright: quiet some drift.
Boma: Yeah, my… I had, I wanted to suggest we take it to ACDE. I don't know if that, sorry, ACDE, I don't know if that would make sense, because…
Boma: of the different… first of all, the different, client implementation that I stated out on the issue itself, then…
Boma: If the ZKVM team, I think CAVE, I don't know if I'm pronouncing his name correctly.
Boma: to sort of chime in on this, Paul.
Boma: I don't know if I should take it, or you want to continue, since you already started the PL on it.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I don't… I don't know. I… like, I'm not… I don't really work on the ZKVM stuff, so I don't know.
Chase Wright: It… every client needs changes, to, like…
Boma: Yes.
Chase Wright: at each other, so I don't know.
Boma: What I'm saying is, should we bring it up to ACDE for them to look into?
Chase Wright: Sure.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: Thank you.
Stavros Vlachakis: Maybe it would be useful to bring it up on some ZK EVM call.
Boma: I don't know, I'm… Okay, I don't really know if they have calls for ZKVM.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Yeah, hello,
Kevaundray Wedderburn: I… yeah, I don't know what input is needed, but there is a zkVM monthly call…
Kevaundray Wedderburn: it might be in the PM slash issues, or we might not have created it yet, but it's in about 2 weeks,
Kevaundray Wedderburn: So not next week, but the week after, next.
Boma: Oh, okay, so we have this, issue on debug execution witness. We wanted,
Boma: you guys to… I'm sharing my screen, I don't know if you can see it. I don't really know how to share a link and then open the chat on Zoom. So we have this, issue, and we would like, the team to take a look at it and comment on it, because currently,
Boma: Various clients have different themes implemented.
Boma: This is the issue details. So, we want to, like, know what should be spec'd, and then how client Zoom should actually, like, go about it.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Okay, yeah, makes sense. So…
Kevaundray Wedderburn: We also have the specs, at least for what this thing returns in the execution specs. And we've been testing some of the clients against it, because this is where, like, most of the discrepancies come from.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: There are some, yeah, minor discrepancies with the format that gets returned, as in, like, some return the keys and others don't include the keys. But yeah, in terms of things being returned, it's really being spec'd or tested using the execution specs.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: I don't know if that makes, sense. I can also get the link to this, and…
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Send it to Zoom…
Boma: So, yeah, I can send you the link, but I'm not sure… I have to, like, stop sharing. I don't know how to, like, operate Zoom perfectly.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Oh, I could just… Complain.
Boma: I can't find the chart.
Boma: Hmm…
Kevaundray Wedderburn: I could look at the repository, execution apiary…
Boma: Yeah, I just sent it on the chat.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Oh, okay.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Okay, thanks.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Yeah, I can definitely review this and also send it to folks to look at as well. I think it's fairly non-controversial.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: In terms of what should be returned?
Kevaundray Wedderburn: So it should be okay to review.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Headers, code, state… yep.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Maybe one… comment…
Kevaundray Wedderburn: or is my, maybe, ignorance, but in terms of versioning, how would this work? Because once we have a different state try, we would essentially change
Kevaundray Wedderburn: The state field, for example.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: And, well, likely most of these things.
Chase Wright: So…
Chase Wright: I mean, historically, JSON RPC hasn't dealt with versioning very well. So, really, we have two options. One, we can… we can stick a V1 prefix on the API itself.
Chase Wright: and then move to a V2, in the future. Or, you know.
Chase Wright: every… every other method that doesn't have a V prefix, we just…
Chase Wright: You know, we retroactively update it and change it,
Chase Wright: In the very near future, we hope to have releases for the JSON RPC specs.
Chase Wright: So we could… we could deal with it that way as well.
Chase Wright: Or, there could be versioning information returned within the, you know, body of the response,
Chase Wright: I don't… I don't really know the best way to handle that.
Chase Wright: EIPIs?
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Okay, yeah, so I guess it seems like a general thing. The issue that I mentioned also comes up with EF Get proofs, because that's somewhat linked to the current state tree, so we'd have it there as well. So yeah, I guess it's a general issue on versioning.
Boma: Yeah, I actually have, it has a question for the agenda, because we also need to figure that out, which I'm not sure how.
Boma: We are going to do that. Although it was Kira that was… Pushing this forward before.
Boma: Boya, I don't really have an idea on how we're going to go about it, the best way to go about it.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Yeah, makes sense. Yeah, I guess it's not super important now, but it might be good to be forward-looking, in the future.
Boma: Yeah, we'll definitely find a way to do this, then I think, hopefully, we'll be able to do it soon. We did a pre-release sometimes to test how the versioning works, but…
Boma: View.
Boma: So, moving on to the Nest PR, which is this… It's 01.
Boma: I guess since you have Mejean Wright, is this okay?
Chase Wright: So, if you would have asked me 3 days ago, I would have said, yes, it's okay, and we can probably merge it. I didn't really want to…
Chase Wright: approve and merge my own PR. However, if you look at 787, which is the… the issue that this PR was… or the…
Chase Wright: the superseded pull request.
Chase Wright: Someone replied 2 days ago, with…
Chase Wright: small comments and questions to clarify. So, I haven't looked at it yet.
Chase Wright: So I think… I think we need to look at those comments and questions, maybe address them.
Chase Wright: And then… if needed, update the PR. So I… I don't… I don't know the answer right this minute.
Boma: Sorry, does anyone have any comments on this?
Boma: I guess not. Maybe we can tag Felix to it.
Chase Wright: I mean, I just haven't had any time to review the feedback and questions. I know there's a question in Discord
Chase Wright: about, testing build block?
Chase Wright: not working, or something. So, we gotta look at it. I think we can just backlog this one for this week and come back to it.
Boma: Yeah.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: Then it's December 1. Okay. Yep.
Boma: We can look at H5-1.
Boma: But we also have in mind that BAO doesn't have, like, a test, the .io files are not well created, if there is a .io files in here.
Chase Wright: So, I haven't had a chance to test or look at this one. I mean, it… it looks fine on the surface, but I… I haven't tested it. I don't know if it even needs new IO phones.
Chase Wright: It might.
Boma: Yeah, and also, the BAO implementation, there is no .io files for it yet. We have it, like, on,
Boma: A pending list of things to do.
Chase Wright: Because the first.
Boma: SPO.
Boma: was merged without the .io files, as I think there was no Get implementation of it, or something happened. I can't recall what exactly.
Chase Wright: Right, so for that, we need Glamsterdam support, right? And so…
Chase Wright: I have. I think we talked about it in another issue, but we don't… we don't have Glamsterdam support in HiveChain yet.
Chase Wright: So we can't test bells yet.
Boma: Do we approve this? It's 5-1?
Chase Wright: I don't know, I need to… I need to test it. I… I haven't had time.
Chase Wright: I'll do it… I'll do it probably today.
Chase Wright: I'll look at it.
Boma: Okay, I already, tagged Terrence on this.
Boma: Okay, you also approved it, some hours ago. Is it okay if we match it, or…
Chase Wright: I think so. I mean, I was waiting for this call to see if anyone had any concerns, but it's just a two-line…
Chase Wright: This is a two-line change to identification markdown.
Chase Wright: I think it's mine.
Boma: Yeah, because I already tagged, Terrence on the group chat to look into it, because there was something added after his initial approval.
Boma: Then we have this… this has been pending for, like, the wow now.
Boma: Although, felix had a comment on it, so I'm not really sure what… under conflicts.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I don't know.
Boma: Question is… Do we tag, Carrie to, like, update the PR? Is this something she can do?
Chase Wright: I don't know if Carrie is working on RPC standards anymore.
Boma: Yeah, that backs my question. Do we tag her, or do we need to?
Boma: Holy cow.
Boma: She isn't okay.
Boma: Thank you.
Boma: Does it make sense? I don't know if the PR actually… because, Felix had,
Boma: Some comments about it, and he assigned himself to it, so…
Boma: Do we drop this from feature calls for now, or…
Boma: we can make a new PR and then continue the conversation.
Chase Wright: I think we should just drop it for now.
Chase Wright: And… Come back to it.
Boma: Okay.
Boma: So most of the PRs are actually from you.
Boma: And… we… I'm not really sure what this is about, but you already made a comment about it.
Chase Wright: Yeah, so this is… so, this is two parts. The first part is… is specifying Call Tracer, which…
Chase Wright: I agree we should do and want to do, but…
Chase Wright: this particular two-dimensional gas tracing is part of Glamsterdam, I think?
Chase Wright: And so, as I said, there are two Hive PRs.
Chase Wright: Doing this… So, this is just on hold.
Chase Wright: Until we can get… Hive support.
Boma: Okay, I guess the best person to look into it is Felix. Or do you have access to Mejing Rights on Hive?
Chase Wright: I do not.
Chase Wright: And also, I'm… these are semi-vibe-coded PRs that I'm not 100% confident in, so someone with more EVM experience than me should definitely review them.
Boma: Yeah, I also don't understand, Hive most of the time, so…
Chase Wright: lightclient might be able to help.
Boma: Yeah.
Boma: Terrella, Clint, do you have any comments on this?
lightclient: I would have to look at.
Boma: Okay, thank you.
Boma: And I think the last is this…
Boma: Yeah.
Boma: We had this pending, and…
Boma: the PR… this is supposed to go in, but I'm not sure what's still holding up, because the other PR that was blocking this got matched a very long time ago.
Chase Wright: Yeah, I mean, we've talked about the ET Subscribe thing on, like, 3… 3 different calls, and…
Chase Wright: I don't think anyone really has an opinion. So, like, if we merge this as is, we're just merging this… the spec file?
Chase Wright: And there's no tests for it.
Chase Wright: And… it's really hard to, probably, to generate Tests for it.
Chase Wright: So I don't really have an opinion, same answer I gave the last 3 calls, like…
Chase Wright: We could just merge it, and say this is the spec, and then… Not deal with the tests.
Chase Wright: It wouldn't be the first time.
Boma: Or will it be okay to merge it and then do with the test later on?
Chase Wright: Yeah, I mean, I guess it's okay. I don't know if anyone else has an opinion.
Boma: Sorry, does anyone have an opinion on this pair?
Boma: I guess not. I think that's, like, all we have on the agenda for today, Dan. We already touched about the release.
Boma: I don't know if anyone else has something to say or add to the chat, to the agenda.
Boma: Or any comments on how we are going to… better ways we are going to, like, do the official release for API?
Boma: I guess not also.
Boma: I think we can call it a day.
Boma: Thank you all for joining the call, and see you next time, next two weeks.
Kevaundray Wedderburn: Great, thank you.
Boma: Oh, oh, so, okay, I think Sim is here. Sorry, I'm so sorry for trying to end the call. We, we did have a talk on, the error codes.
Boma: I don't know if Sim has any update on it, although the main update was supposed to come from Simra and then Felix, but they are still not in the call, so I don't know if.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Yeah.
Boma: Updates based on that.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Yeah, exactly.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Yeah, I was just waiting for them to join and give some opinions, because the last time I asked, they said the discussion was still ongoing.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: I don't believe we have any concrete updates on this.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Maybe it's, it's best if we can…
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: You know, jump on a breakout call or something when everyone is available.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: And sort this through, and not wait for this, maybe?
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: I did propose that, haven't gotten any update, but maybe I'll follow up on it again.
Boma: Okay, I don't really know
Boma: I don't know if Chase has something else to say.
Boma: Because the… the whole… the last call which Felix joined, he said, Simra was working on it, so I'm not sure of…
Boma: Any other photo development, and…
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Yeah.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Yeah, same. Yeah, I was just, hoping to join today's…
Chase Wright: Yeah, I don't have any insight either, other than what Felix said in the last call. I don't know if CINA is working on JSON RPC Standards anymore, either.
Boma: Wait, I think I tagged him on the chat, okay, okay.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: I mean, if we don't catch any update, maybe in the next 2 weeks, probably. I personally would prefer to go with, Chase's PR.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: With just some slight modification.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: to be honest, I think it's better to keep the, concerns of, eat, simulate separate than what we're just trying to do.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: And then, maybe error codes B2 or Simulate B2 can try and address that.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Because it's currently blocking anyone to actually implement and make use of these error codes.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: That's… that's just my two cents. Maybe… maybe we'll wait for Felix also in the next meeting.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Or, or we can start a thread again.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Yeah, that's the only thing that's blocking currently, isn't it? I think, Eat Simulate is the only thing that's bringing some confusion into the mix.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: If you just keep that separate.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: you know, consens really separate. I think we should be okay to… to just, you know, go ahead with Chase's PR. It wasn't draft, I believe, but we can take a look at this one more time.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: The next meeting.
Boma: But will it be okay for you to, like, open a trade on, Discord so that,
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Yeah, I already did. I'll try to respond in the same thread again.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Maybe, maybe this time I'll get some answers, but yeah, I'll follow up on the thread.
Boma: Okay, alright.
Boma: So thank you very much for keeping up with this.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Oh, miss.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Thank you, guys.
Boma: Alright.
Boma: I think that's, like, the last thing. Thank you all for joining. See you next time, next two weeks, yeah.
Simsonraj Easvarasakthi: Thank you, everyone. Bye-bye.
Boma: Bye.
Stavros Vlachakis: Bye.
Boma: Oh…